hey everyone welcome back to another
interesting lesson in this tosa
automation playlist today I'm going to
talk about an interesting feature which
is available in tosa and this is
especially when you add a verification
step so you must be using the action
mode verify in your test steps and then
only you can make use of this particular
feature now this is something called
intervals okay and using this interval
in action mode verify we can verify not
just any particular value but we can
verify if a value lies within the
specific range which is defined by us
now think about scenarios where you
don't have any particular value or the
value keeps on changing but it is still
within uh numerical range so in these
type of scenarios you can make use of
something called intervals
now keep in mind that uh the data types
where it can be applied is only limited
to numeric or string okay so your data
type should be a numeric or
string then uh you can only uh make
comparisons like uh you can use the
equals equals uh operator or you can use
the not equals
operator now there are basically two
types of intervals uh which are present
in tosa one is the simple interval
so here you have an interval with equal
upper and lower boundaries now the
syntax it looks like this so you start
with curly brace and then you uh type
interval that is the expression inside
that uh you will then Define a base
value and then you will Define a limit
okay now the range uh in which uh this
verification will be successful is uh
the base minus limit and base plus limit
so if the number which you have provided
or the number which you're trying to
verify Falls within this particular
range then um this particular
verification will be successful
otherwise it will fail okay so this is
known as a simple interval then there is
also a custom interval where you have an
interval with unique upper and lower
boundaries okay so in this the syntax
changes a little bit you have the
interval expression and then you have
got the base uh value and then you have
got the lower boundary and also the
upper boundary okay so in this the valid
range would lie between the base minus a
lower boundary and a base plus upper
boundary okay so you can test your range
within different boundaries one upper
and one lower in case of custom interval
but in case of simple interval uh the
upper and lower boundaries will be equal
so you will you can only test within
that particular uh limit okay so this is
how the intervals work in tosa now let's
try to understand this with a very
simple example
okay so here I have got the vehicle
insurance application and then when you
fill all the vehicle data Insurance data
and product data you reach the screen
where it shows you different price price
options for different plans and then you
need to select a particular price option
right the one scenario where you can use
interval in this is the claims discount
now depending on what data a user is
entering in the vehicle insurance or
product data this claims discount will
keep on changing but it will be within a
particular range say for example this is
between uh 2 and 10 right all of this
numbers are between two and 10 so the
discount ranges uh between a particular
range right and then if you're trying to
verify some like something like for this
gold option or platinum option you can
verify the range uh like from 2 to 10 or
5 to 10 right so even if uh the claim
discount changes uh for any particular
data still if it falls within that
particular range then the test case
should pass uh it should fail right so
in this way you are not dependent on a
static value uh which is being displayed
here you can define a particular range
based on the requirements of the
application and then uh you can decide
whether uh the value which is displayed
in the application Falls within that
particular range and it meets the
requirements and then you can pass or
fail the test case
right so let's see how we can do this so
so I have already scanned the module
select price option it is just a table
with different rows and columns right
and then we are using this particular
test case to verify the discount here
and I am going to now uh select this
test case and pull this module right
here okay so as you can see it is a
table and then it has got different rows
and columns right now in order to verify
let's say the claim discount for
platinum option right so I need to uh go
to this Platinum column and then I need
to find uh the value for claim discount
right so here um I need to select in the
column option I'm going to select
platinum and then uh in the cell okay I
am going to find this particular cell
right and it will take up this
particular value okay
so instead of sell I'm going to just
type the complete text here okay so in
the value it will get uh the five as the
value okay and that uh we can verify as
well okay so let's see whether it is
actually doing that and uh I'm going to
say bore discount which is the buffer
value okay so it will store that
discount in the buffer it is just to
make sure that it is actually capturing
that particular value okay so uh let's
just run this first and then we'll see
how we can use the interval here
okay okay so the execution was completed
and uh if I go through the logs you will
see that the B discount has a value five
so it is grabbing the correct value from
the table okay now uh what I want to do
is I don't want to verify this
five as the discount value I want to
make it a interval right I want to
verify it within arrange so for that uh
let's now again copy this and put this
inside another cell and this time around
I'm going to verify that so let's uh
prepare the expression so it will be as
I said
interval when you type this you will get
uh the description here the syntax uh
and also an example
right so uh let's do this interval and
then uh the square bracket okay now uh
we need to look at the calculation so if
you look at the calculation if you're
doing a simple interval right so we need
to provide the base and then the limit
and then the range should be between
base minus limit and base plus limit
okay so say for example I give uh some
range like base I will give a value 10
here okay and then limit I will give
five so what will happen here is um the
value should be in the range of 10 minus
5 which is 5 and then 10 + 5 which is 15
so the range the valid range here is
five and and 15 so any number between
five and 15 should be verified
successfully okay so let's run this test
case now
again okay so the execution was
completed and now as you can see the
test result was passed okay so this is
where it is trying to verify within the
interval uh here it has captured it in
the buffer in the log info you will not
find any log L here but if the test case
is pass that means the interval uh was
successfully verified
okay similarly um if you want to do a
custom interval right so this was an
example of simple interval right so if
if you want to do a custom interval so
where uh we need to provide a base and
then we have to provide a lower boundary
and then we have to also provide a upper
boundary right so so here again I'm
going to put the base is 10 the lower
boundary as five and the upper boundary
as five okay so it will look like this
now here the valid range is um 10 - 5
right and then uh 10 + 5 okay so if you
look at the calculation so it is base
minus lower boundary and base plus upper
boundary okay so it is basically the
same calculation but here you have the
option to provide a upper and lower
boundary okay now if I go ahead and run
this for the final time all the
verifications should have passed right
and the value should be stored in the
buffer okay so test case has passed and
you can see both verifications has have
also passed okay so both the intervals
are system and simple interval have uh
successfully
verified so similarly you can use uh
this interval uh to verify any
particular numbers which are displayed
here or even strings right so you can
play around with uh the upper and lower
boundary for custom interval or just the
limit for the simple
interval that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video